Dale Newbold

Senior DevOps Engineer(AWS, Azure, GCP, Kubernetes, Terraform)

Address: 1435 Southwest 15th Avenue Ocala, FL 34471 United States

Email: newbolddan242@gmail.com

I am a senior DevOps Engineer/Solution Architect who has rich experience with Digital Ocean, Linode platforms, Automation using Ansible, AWS Service, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Docker, Jinkins for CI/CD, Github, and Bitbucket.

My Skills:

- * DevOps/Solution Architect with 8+ years of experience in administration, automation, and systems monitoring
- * Capacity planning and systems monitoring;
- * Excellent knowledge of systems programming, shell (bash) usage, Linux/UNIX commands;
- *Performance tuning, benchmarking, troubleshooting, debugging and systems scaling skills;
- * Ability to use a wide variety of open source technologies and tools;
- * Ability to code and script in Python, Perl, Ruby and Golang

I have rich experience with CI/CD pipelines implementation as well using the most popular current toolsets - CircleCI, Azure DevOps, AWS CodeDeploy, etc. I am confident with my DevOps Engineering background and experience for best practices, and I will be able to resolve all solutions myself from CI/CD, Cloud Migration, Infrastructure Scaling, System Architecture, and more

With most of my projects, I was responsible for everything from ground up including the development lifecycle, automated release pipelines, automated deployments, version control, and Infrastructure-as-Code.

I have used a wide array of different DevOps tools in past projects include: Terraform, Packer, Ansible, CloudFormation, Jenkins, CircleCI, TravisCI, Github, Docker, Kubernetes, and more

EXPERIENCE

Whitepages July 2019 - October 2022

Senior Devops Engineer and Solution Architect

- Responsible for DevOps Architecture, Infrastructure Automations (Terraform, ARM), Rearchitecture, transformation, migration and implementation of (Customer's) Custom Application/Infrastructure on Azure IaaS and PaaS cloud solutions.
- Responsible for AWS & Azure Customer discovery, assessment, technical engagement, service validation, monthly reviews.
- Build and release, provisioning, capacity planning, Reporting, Configuration Management and Manage continuous deployment of custom Applications.
- Administer & Manage: GCP Partner Portal, Microsoft Partner, Microsoft Azure MSP CSP Subscription, Azure DevOps, JIRA, CloudSphere, PRISMA, OPSRamp.
- Design and implement AWS/GCP & Azure IaaS and PaaS technology solutions for client's business needs, security, and service level requirement and conduct proof of concept (POC).
- Building and deploying applications in Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services and Google Compute Platform

Contix April 2015 - April 2018

Senior Devops Engineer

- o Publish Product new version on Microsoft Azure Marketplace.
- o Build DevOps Architecture in Azure DevOps and Maintained CI/CD for the Application Infrastructure hosted in Azure.
- o Prepared test environment for the product on Hyper-V (Application Server, Encoding Server, Storage Server, SQL Server 2017 Enterprise, ADFS Server, ID-Connector Server, ForgeRock Open-AM SSO Server, WOWZA Storage Server).
- o Deployed Staging environment of the Product new version on Azure Cloud.
- o Deployed Virtual Machine Scale Set on Azure for Product.
- o Automated installation of new version Product with PowerShell.
- o SSO Integrations for (Azure AD, ForgeRock, Okta, PingID, OneLogin, ADFS, SAML-P)

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University

July 2006 - November 2010

Master of Computer Applications (MCA)

SKILLS

- * DevOps/Solution Architect with 8+ years of experience in administration, automation, and systems monitoring
- * Capacity planning and systems monitoring;
- * Excellent knowledge of systems programming, shell (bash) usage, Linux/UNIX commands;
- * Performance tuning, benchmarking, troubleshooting, debugging and systems scaling skills;
- * Ability to use a wide variety of open source technologies and tools;
- * Ability to code and script in Python, Perl, Ruby and Golang;